Jing Mai

Science Building #5, Peking University, No.5 Yiheyuan Road, Haidian District, Beijing 1000871 jingmai@pku.edu.edu magic3007.github.io

Bio

I am a second-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science at Peking University associated with the Center for Energy-Efficient Computing and Applications (CECA). I am a member of the PKU-IDEA Lab, advised by Prof. Yibo Lin. Previously, I received the B.S. degree in Computer Science and Technology from Peking University in 2021. My research focuses are machine learning-assisted EDA; my broader interests include MLSys, concurrency and probabilistic modeling.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Center for Energy-efficient Computing and Applications (CECA), Peking University

Advisor: Prof. Yibo Lin

B.S. in Computer Science and Technology

School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science (EECS), Peking University

Sept. 2021 - Present Beijing, China

Beijing, China

Sept. 2017 – June 2021

Publications

(* denotes alphabetical ordering or equal contribution)

Refereed Conference Papers

[C1] Jiarui Wang, Jing Mai, Zhixiong Di, Yibo Lin. A Robust FPGA Router with Concurrent Intra-CLB Rerouting. 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (ASP-DAC), 2023.

[C2] Yifan Chen, Jing Mai, Xiaohan Gao, Muhan Zhang, Yibo Lin. MacroRank: Ranking Macro Placement Solutions Leveraging Translation Equivariancy. 28th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (ASP-DAC), 2023.

[C3] Jing Mai, Yibai Meng, Zhixiong Di, Yibo Lin. Multi-Electrostatic FPGA Placement Considering SLICEL-SLICEM Heterogeneity and Clock Feasibility. 59th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (**DAC**), 2022.

[C4] Jing Mai*, Zizheng Guo*, Yibo Lin. Ultrafast CPU/GPU Kernels for Density Accumulation in Placement. 58th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (**DAC**), 2021.

Journal Papers

[J1] Yihua Cheng, Zejia Fan, Jing Mai, Yifan Wu, Pengcheng Xu, Yuxuan Yan, Zhenxin Fu, Yun Liang. Critique of "Planetary Normal Mode Computation: Parallel Algorithms, Performance, and Reproducibility" by SCC Team From Peking University. IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (IEEE Trans Parallel Distrib Syst), 2021.

Research Experiences

Nanjing Industrial Innovation Center of EDA (NiCEDA)

Software Development Intern

Topics: Dataflow-driven global placement

Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK)

Summer Intern, co-advised by Prof. Yibo Lin and Prof. Bei Yu Topics: Electrostatics-Based global placement for FPGAs Aug 2021 - Sept. 2021

Shanghai, China

July 2020 - Aug 2020

Shenzhen, China

Honors and Awards

 The 3rd EDA Elite Challenge (Second Prize) 	Dec 2021
 Honors for Outstanding Undergraduate Graduates in Beijing (top 1%) 	May 2021
Beijing Challenge Cup Competition (Second Prize)	May 2021
Xiaomi Scholarship, Peking University	Dec 2020
 Honors for Merit Student, Peking University (top 5%) 	Dec 2019, Dec 2020
 Huawei Scholarship, Peking University 	Dec 2019
 Honors for Outstanding Academic Performance, Peking University 	Dec 2018
The 43rd ACM-ICPC Asia Regional Competition (Gold Award)	Nov 2018

Teaching and Mentoring Experience

• **Teaching Assistant** – Optimization and Machine Learning in VLSI Design Automation, Peking University

2022

Skills

Programming Languages and Softwares

C/C++, Python, Java, Pytorch, Tensorflow, MTpX, Git, CUDA, Docker, Data Analysis/Visualization(Pandas)

Web Development

HTML5, JavaScript

EDA Tools

Xilinx Vivado

Languages

Mandarin, Cantonese, English, Japanese